[Music]
foreign
Advanced Training
so this is our lesson 22
in terms of overall try sentence Tasker
training
R it's a lesson 7 in terms of Advanced
Training so I would recommend you guys
to please visit my previous videos
before you watch this session to
understand the concepts very well
so in this lesson I'm going to teach you
how can you use a dynamic comparison or
how can you perform Dynamic comparison
while automating your test cases are
while validating your
test cases by using tricentish task
automation
so Dynamic for dynamic comparison we use
x buffer so you're gonna learn X buffer
Concept in this particular training
session
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
okay
so what is dynamic comparison
so in this lesson you I'm gonna teach
you how can you set up and then how to
use Dynamic comparison
and the dynamic comparison is a feature
within Tosca that allows you to verify a
portion of the string that is static so
basically you can verify static portion
of the string and you can buffer another
portion of the string which is dynamic
okay so let's assume once you order your
product in any e-commerce site right it
says your order has been successfully
placed and it gives you the order number
so in this case the order number is a
dynamic and your order has been
successfully placed that is a static
text so now how can you validate this
entire string
part of string is dynamic and part of
string is static so that is where
this Dynamic comparison comes into
picture
okay so this is also represented as X
buffer which is Curly braces XB in Tosca
so basically this helps you to verify
the string with Dynamic elements
and as well as simultaneously
you can buffer the element within the
string which is a dynamic and you can
utilize them later in your test
validations
okay so let's jump onto the system and
see how can we perform this Dynamic
comparison by using X buffer concept by
using latest version try sentence task
16.
so this is my task 16 okay where we are
going to start working on Dynamic
comparison so if you see I already
explained you one end to end scenario
where
we go to if you see this is my demo web
shop
that is where we are working from past
21 sessions okay you log I mean you
basically logged into demo webshop go to
operation shoes so I'm gonna teach you I
mean I'm gonna tell you what scenario we
are automating here okay and go to Blue
Jeans
and add to cart quantity one
okay and then go to shopping cart
and here agree the terms
check out
and here
billing address
shipping address so this is all already
I explained you okay guys okay so here
once you complete your
entire order once you confirm the order
you will get an order number okay so if
you see here this text order number
140912 correct so here order number is a
static
and
1401912 is dynamic text
okay so that means now I want to verify
this text how can I verify this text
so that is where Dynamic comparison
comes into picture so let's go here so I
already automated that entire scenario
logging in and then check out and verify
so here if you see there is one module
test case step called verify the order
success where I am verifying the
successful order your order has been
successfully processed and here the
order number okay what I'm gonna do here
I'm gonna verify this also select verify
and here inner text this is my object
control related to this one okay here
I'm gonna select
inner text
and my inner text is equal to my inner
text is equal to what here copy this
okay
copy this
and paste here sorry this one inner text
equal to here this is my Dynamic part
right that one
I'm gonna specify as X buffer
exclude
the verification
and buffer this particular text this
particular part of the string and what
I'm doing I am specifying verify this
entire text from here to here
and while verifying exclude this part
and then store this in a buffer value
okay so for that that's the reason I'm
going to specify x b x buffer here I'm
gonna tell this as order number what I'm
doing this particular string after order
number whatever exists
exclude that
in the verification and store it into
buffer called order number
that's it
so now if you see
I am verifying this entire State text
entire string but I'm excluding the part
of string and storing that particular
order number into order number
buffer okay so now we are done
so basically before you make any changes
it's recommended to
resolve the references
because this actually we created by
using Library
so Library functions and all these
things I already explained you guys okay
so now
here
I want to run this particular test case
as it is okay let me first log out here
and close this website
okay now right click and run in
scratchbook which opens your webshop and
it logs into webshop
so logging in providing the credentials
and then go to appearance and choose
and it orders the genes
is going to add that into card see it's
adding into the cut
done 25 amount go to shopping cart agree
terms
so basically it is applying the coupon
agree terms
check out
click on continue continue and then it
is actually shipping method it's
selecting payment method
right and it's selecting
the credit card and then it's click on
confirm so once you click on confirm
it's going to verify the success message
and it's going to verify this also right
and then it's going to log out
okay it's done logged out so if you see
here
successfully completed so if I go to
test results if I go to test results
let's go to test results now if you see
here under shopping cart
procedure here verify order success if
you see here
it says this order number verification
is successful and the order number is
placed here okay so let me see the
buffer how does it buffer stored okay
let's go to tools and click on Buffer
overview and if you see here order
number see buffer called order number is
stored with actual order number
so you have to go to tools click on
Buffer viewer
see this is where I see the order number
whatever the buffer I specified I can
see here see this is the order number XB
so that order number has been placed
correct so now I can use this order
number to verify the order number right
so hope you all understand the concept
of dynamic comparison how can you
validate a message which is a dynamic
some portion of the message is static
and some portion of the message is
dynamic okay so if you have any queries
leave your comments in the comment box
I'll try to respond to your queries
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you